<resources>
    <!-- APP DETAILS -->
    <string name="app_name" translatable="false">ChipDefense: Copper</string>
    <string name="app_description">Chip Defense is a casual tower defense game for Android inspired by electronic circuits and logic chips, evoking the nostalgic era of 8-bit microprocessors.</string>

    <!-- GENERAL -->
    <string name="go_back">Go back</string>
    <string name="name_series_1">Normal</string>
    <string name="name_series_2">Turbo</string>
    <string name="name_series_3">Endless</string>

    <!-- HOME -->
    <string name="button_start_game">Start new game</string>
    <string name="button_resume">Resume game</string>
    <string name="selectLevel">Select Level</string>
    <string name="button_info">About The Game</string>
    <string name="button_exit">Exit Game</string>
    <string name="play_level_x">Play level %s</string>
    <string name="stage_reached">Stage reached: %1$s %2$d</string>

    <!-- SETTINGS -->
    <string name="settings_title">Settings</string>
    <string name="settings_use_large_buttons">Use large objects</string>
    <string name="settings_show_framerate">Show frame rate</string>
    <string name="settings_keep_levels">Keep created stages in “endless” mode</string>
    <string name="settings_use_hex">Display stage numbers in hex</string>
    <string name="game_progress">Game Progress</string>
    <string name="import_data">Import Data</string>
    <string name="export_data">Export Data</string>
    <string name="button_reset_progress">Reset game progress</string>
    <string name="settings_activate_log">Enable debug logging</string>
    <string name="settings_fast_fast_forward">Show “really fast forward” button</string>
    <string name="settings_disable_purchase_dialog">Disable the life purchase dialog</string>
    <string name="settings_disable_background">Disable background</string>
    <string name="settings_show_atts_in_range">Show attackers in range</string>

    <!-- ABOUT -->
    <string name="chip_defense_copper_url" translatable="false">https://github.com/jmiguelrivas/chip-defense-copper</string>
    <string name="chip_defense_copper_label" translatable="false">jmiguelrivas/chip-defense-copper</string>
    <string name="chip_defense_url" translatable="false">https://github.com/ochadenas/cpudefense</string>
    <string name="chip_defense_label" translatable="false">ochadenas/cpudefense</string>
    <string name="wiki_url" translatable="false">https://github.com/ochadenas/cpudefense/wiki/Chip-Defense</string>
    <string name="wiki_label">Game Wiki (ChipDefense)</string>
    <string name="works_offline">Works Offline</string>
    <string name="no_trackers">No Trackers</string>
    <string name="no_ads">No Ads</string>
    <string name="license">License MIT</string>

    <!-- LEVEL SELECTOR -->
    <string name="play_selected_level">Play selected level</string>
    <string name="coins_got">%1$d / %2$d coin</string>
    <string name="coins_got_plural">%1$d / %2$d coins</string>
    <string name="level_entry">Level %s</string>
    <string name="message_series_unavailable">Complete all levels in “normal” mode first.</string>
    <string name="message_endless_unavailable">Complete all levels in “turbo” mode first.</string>

    <!-- MODAL :: RESET GAME PROGRESS -->
    <string name="query_restart_game">Do you want to reset all your current progress?</string>
    <string name="reset_all_progress">Reset all my progress</string>
    <string name="reset_endless">Only reset endless mode</string>
    <string name="cancel">Cancel</string>

    <!-- MODAL :: RESET STAGE -->
    <string name="buttton_replay">Reset stage</string>
    <string name="button_return_to_main_menu">Return to main menu</string>
    <string name="continue_game">Continue playing</string>

    <!-- INTERMEZZO -->
    <string name="series_completed_message_1">" "</string>
    <string name="series_completed_message_4">" "</string>
    <string name="game_start">Starting game.</string>
    <string name="button_playlevel">Play stage</string>
    <string name="failed">Failed to clear stage.</string>
    <string name="coins_gathered">Coins gathered: %d.</string>
    <string name="success">All stages cleared!</string>
    <string name="next_stage">Next stage: %s</string>
    <string name="cleared">Stage cleared.</string>
    <string name="last_stage">Last stage was: %s</string>
    <string name="win">You win.</string>
    <string name="button_retry">Retry</string>
    <string name="instr_leave">Some heroes are asking for time off. You must grant leave to one of them, who will return after %d levels.</string>
    <string name="instr_leave_1">Some heroes are asking for time off. You must grant leave to one of them, who will return in the next level.</string>
    <string name="heroes_on_leave_0">No heroes are on leave.</string>
    <string name="heroes_on_leave_1">Hero on leave:</string>
    <string name="button_marketplace">Check Heroes</string>

    <!-- MODAL :: RESET HEROES -->
    <string name="query_reset">Do you want to reset all heroes?</string>
    <string name="no">No</string>
    <string name="yes">Yes</string>

    <!-- MODAL :: PURCHASE LIFE -->
    <string name="query_purchase_life">Do you want to spend %s to recover a life?</string>
    <string name="annotation_purchase_life">This dialog can be disabled in “Settings”. You will still be able to purchase lives by tapping on the CPU.</string>

    <!-- GAME -->
    <string name="game_paused">GAME PAUSED</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_status">lives</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_coins">coins</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_inf">inf</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_stage">stage</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_waves">wave</string>
    <string name="scoreboard_temp">temp</string>
    <string name="toast_loading">Loading …</string>
    <string name="overheat">CPU damage from overheating</string>

    <!-- MERKETPLACE -->
    <string name="button_refund_all">Reset all Heroes</string>
    <string name="button_refund_one">Downgrade Hero</string>
    <string name="button_purchase">Upgrade Hero [1 coin] </string>
    <string name="button_purchase_plural">Upgrade Hero [%d coins]</string>
    <string name="cost_desc">[cost: %d]</string>
    <string name="message_cannot_fire">Use “%s” to release this hero.</string>
    <string name="message_is_on_leave">%s is currently on leave.</string>
    <string name="button_wiki">"Check Wikipedia Bio"</string>
    <string name="coins_available">Coins available: %d</string>
    <string name="coins_received_as_gift">You received %d coins as gift.</string>

    <!-- INSTRUCTIONS -->
    <string name="instr_1">"Your computer is being invaded by an evil virus. Rogue code fragments - shown as Ones and Zeroes - try to get through to the cpu.\n\nTap on the empty slot to add a chip as defense against the attack, and then tap again to confirm your choice.\n\nThe most basic chip is “SUB 1” which subtracts 1 from the attacker´s value. It turns 1´s into 0´s, and it makes 0´s disappear. Only then they are no longer a threat."</string>
    <string name="instr_2">"You may also tap on an attacker. This will invert its value: 1 becomes 0, and 0 becomes 1.\n\nInverting a 0 will actually make the attacker more dangerous, so be careful not to tap on everything you see."</string>
    <string name="instr_3">"The currency in this game is information. It is displayed on the bottom left.\n\nDestroy the attacking code to gain some information about the virus. Use it to buy additional chips or to upgrade the existing ones."    </string>
    <string name="instr_4">"Here are some hints:\n\nRemember that in binary,\n\n10 equals 2,\n11 equals 3,\n100 equals 4,\nand so on.\n\nTry to tap on numbers starting with “1”. This reduces the attacker´s number and makes the level much easier.\n\nAny attacker that gets through to the CPU will cost one life, regardless of its number. You must have at least one SUB chip to get rid of them."</string>
    <string name="instr_5">"In the next level, a new chip type is available. It is labelled “SHR 1”, which means “shift right by 1”.\n\nAll digits are moved one position to the right. The leftmost digit is replaced by 0.\n\nFor example, 0110 becomes 0011. This is equivalent to dividing the value by 2."</string>
    <string name="instr_6">"By clearing stages, you can gain cryptocoins. These coins are valuable. You can use them to hire some powerful Heroes of the Information Age who will give you significant advantages in the game.\n\nThere is a maximum amount of cryptocoins per level shown on the bottom, and each life lost will reduce the reward.\n\nIf you do not get all the coins, you can always replay the level. However, once you have obtained the maximum, you won´t receive any more coins for this stage."</string>
    <string name="instr_7">"Sometimes you will see a cryptocoin moving along with the attackers. You can collect it by destroying it, even multiple times when you replay the level.\n\nBut be careful. The moving cryptocoin is stronger than ordinary attackers, and if it reaches the CPU, it will take one of your lives."</string>
    <string name="instr_7a">Chips need to cool down between operations. Hire heroes to reduce the chance of grouped attackers overwhelming a chip.\n\nIf you are stuck, you can replay a lower level trying to catch a running cryptocoin.</string>
    <string name="instr_8">"\nYou can sell existing chips and re-use their slot. Most, but not all of the information will be refunded.\n\nNote that an activated chip will complete its current cooldown cycle before disappearing."</string>
    <string name="instr_9">"\nLet´s introduce another chip. The MEM (for memory) chip takes a number and stores it safely away in memory. A little white indicator shows that there is a value inside.\n\nThe MEM chip must be “read out” (by tapping on it). Once you have tapped on the chip, its cool down cycle starts, and only after that the memory slot becomes available again. A thick white frame indicates whether you should tap on the chip.\n\nFor now, the MEM chip can hold only one attacker,. Later in the game you will be able to buy upgrades, creating additional slots.\n\nMEM chips are powerful because they can take out any attacker, but they require your attention, and they are quite slow."</string>
    <string name="instr_10">"The accumulator chip (ACC) is a bit more complex than the others, but it can be very effective against large numbers of attackers. It takes two numbers and combines them into one result.\n\nIn its basic variant, it adds the two numbers. If you upgrade the chip once, it will OR the input numbers. Upgrading twice makes the operation an AND.\n\nExample: If the numbers 0110 (that is 6) and 0011 (that is 3) enter the ACC chip, the result will be\n1001 (that is 9) when adding [ACC +]\n0111 (that is 7) using OR [ACC v]\n0010 (that is 2) using AND [ACC &amp;].\n\nThe advantage of ACC is that it is really fast."</string>
    <string name="instr_11">"Larger numbers are represented in hexadecimal. They are shown with a leading “x”.\n\nIn hex, you have digits from 0 to 9 and then from A to F. The hex number x0F equals 15, or 1111 in binary."</string>
    <string name="instr_12">"Two more chip types: ADD and SHL.\n\nThese do the opposite of SUB and SHR, respectively: They add 1 to the number and shift the bits to the left.\n\nOf course, this is really undesired. You can “upgrade” these chips to reduce their strength or make them disappear."</string>
    <string name="instr_13">"Note that cryptocoins are unaffected by ACC and also by MEM chips."</string>
    <string name="instr_14">Another chip becomes available! \n\nThe CLK (clock) chip does not affect the attackers itself. Instead, it speeds up the other chips on the board. Each time the CLK ticks, the cooldown timer of all other chips is reset, and they become ready to operate anew.\n\nUpgrading increases the CLK frequency.</string>
    <string name="instr_15">Overclocking the CPU can be dangerous: The faster your chips work, the hotter they will get.\n\nEach time your clock resets a chip, a small amount of heat is produced. Temperatures of more than %d degrees can damage the CPU, that means, that they can cost you one life.</string>
    <string name="instr_16">The NOP chip (No operation) does nothing. But since it occupies a slot, you might want to remove it.\n\nA NOP 2 chip also does nothing, but twice.</string>
    <string name="instr_17">Two more undesired chip types, then we have seen them all.\n\nDUP duplicates an attacking piece of code. Instead of one attacker, you\'ll have two, with the same number.\n\nSPLT (split) does nearly the same, but instead of simply duplicating the number, it splits it into two pieces. For example, xA4 becomes xA0 and x04. This is somewhat the opposite of ACC: If the two resulting numbers are combined by logical OR, you\'ll get the original values.</string>
    <string name="instr_18">Beware! Sneak attack!</string>
    <string name="instr_22">Remember that SHR chips are powerful but cannot eliminate attackers. They quickly reduce large values, but against hordes of weak attackers, multiple SUB chips may be a more cost-effective defence.</string>
    <string name="instr_23">Not all electronic components are logic chips. There are also important classic, analogue components such as capacitors [C] or resistors [R]. \n\nIn this game, resistors have the effect of slowing down the attackers for a certain period of time. Their strength is indicated by three coloured rings. The slowing effect is the bigger the stronger the attackers are. One-bit-numbers are hardly affected at all, whereas 8-bit numbers become quite slow by large resistances.\n\nResistors generate heat. There is a hero (Claude Shannon) who can convert some of this heat into information.</string>
    <string name="instr_endless">You have successfully cleared all stages and won the game!\n\nIf you want, you can continue in “endless” mode, with randomly generated circuits that get more and more difficult. You will start the “endless” series without heroes, and you cannot use the coins gathered until now. \n\nHow far will you get?</string>
    <string name="instr_did_you_know">Did you know?</string>
    <string name="instr_2_98">The heroes will soon be extending their holidays. They will then be unavailable for two or even more stages.</string>
    <string name="series_completed_message_2">You may replay all levels</string>
    <string name="series_completed_message_3">in “turbo” mode now.</string>
    <string name="instr_2_1">"In turbo mode, the attackers are stronger, faster and more numerous.  Furthermore, some slots are already taken by unwanted chips you´ll have to deal with."</string>

    <!-- INSTRUCTIONS :: FUN_FACTS -->
    <string-array name="fun_fact">
        <item>Until 1999, the amount of 1024 B was called a <i>kilobyte</i> (kB). For consistency with other SI units, the kilobyte\'s meaning was changed to 1 kB = 1000 B. To keep the former definition, the kibibyte was invented, with 1 KiB = 1024 B.</item>
        <item>An actual computer bug was found in a Harvard Mark II computer in 1947. A small insect had gotten into a relay, making programs fail.\n\nThe term “bug” for computer errors, however, had been used well before. Already in the 19th century small defects in mechanical devices were called bugs.</item>
        <item>“Bread bin” (or “breadbox”) was a nickname for the Commodore C64, due to its characteristic and not very elegant form.</item>
        <item>In the 1980s, a hole punch was an important tool for computer users, as it allowed the storage capacity of a floppy disc to be doubled.\n\nThe writable side of a floppy disc was determined by the drive using a notch in the cover. If a hole was carefully punched in the opposite side, the disc could be turned over and used from the back.</item>
        <item>If you want to know how a computer actually works, have a look at the excellent site <b>NANDgame.com</b>.\n\nThere, you can build a programmable machine starting only with electric relays. You will find many familiar components, such as ADD or SHR.</item>
        <item>The very first computer adventure game “ADVENT” was developed by William Crowther, who was also a passionate speleologist (a cave explorer).\n\nThe “Colossal Cave” from the game really exists, albeit unfortunately without dragons, dwarfs, or treasures.</item>
        <item>There are 10 types of people in this world: Those who understand binary, and those who don\'t.\n\n\n(Old programmers\' joke.)</item>
        <item>In the “Tales of Pirx the Pilot” by Stanisław Lem, the spaceship “Ariel” crashes on Mars during its landing approach. It turns out that the on-board computer was suffering from a kind of obsessive-compulsive disorder. The more critical the situation became, the more information it requested in its control mania until it could no longer process the amount of data.\n\nA similar situation occurred in reality during the first moon landing. Fortunately for the astronauts, however, the on-board computer was programmed by Margaret Hamilton and her team in such a way that it simply stopped performing less important tasks under stress. Thus it remained operational, and the “Eagle” landed safely on the moon.</item>
        <item>The development of storage capacity over a period of around 60 years is astonishing: a punch card (surface area approx. 156 cm²) has a storage capacity of 80 bytes. A standard microSD memory card today with a surface area of approx. 1.65 cm² and only slightly thicker has a capacity of 256 GB.\n\nThat is a ratio of approx. 1 : 300,000,000,000.\n\nHowever, the back of the punch card can be used to take notes, or write a shopping list. This is not possible with the memory card.</item>
        <item>The keyboard of an IBM 3270 terminal was so sturdy and heavy that some say that it could be used to beat stupid users to death with it.\n\nOthers claim that they have actually done so.</item>
        <item>In the ASCII character set, which we know today as ISO-8859, there are still reminders of its origins as a telegraph alphabet. For example, the ASCII code 07 (“BEL”) is used to ring a small bell on a teletypewriter.</item>
        <item>Long before the invention of the touchscreen, there was the light pen. This pen-shaped device was connected to the computer by a cable and could determine its position on the screen. To do this, it had a light-sensitive photocell at its tip.\n\nIn CRT monitors, the electron beam creates the image line by line. By measuring the exact time of the light flash perceived by the pen, the current position of the beam and thus also of the pen could be determined.\n\nThe light pen became obsolete by computer mice, and the principle does not work with modern flat screens anyway.</item>
        <item>In the 1990s, the programme “xsnow” was very popular on Unix computers. It made snowflakes gently fall down on the desktop background, building heaps on the top of the programme windows. From time to time the flakes were swirled by the wind, and sometimes you could see Santa Claus flying across the screen in a reindeer sleigh. The -showrudolph option determined whether the foremost reindeer had a red nose.</item>
        <item>Snacks are good in moderation.\n\n\n(“Tip of the day” in Civilization IV)</item>
        <item>To subtract one number from another in the binary system, you don\'t need to know how to subtract. Instead, you invert the number, add 1 and add the result.\n\nWhy does this work? If you invert a number - for example 0101 1110 (x5E) into 1010 0001 (xA1) - and add the two together, you always get 1111 1111 (i.e. xFF). Add 1 and discard the carry, this will yield 0000 0000. You can therefore interpret the number xA2 (i.e. xA1 plus 1) as “minus x5E”. Example: x7F - x5E is x21, and x7F + xA2 (shortened to 8 bits) is also x21.</item>
        <item>A “pizza box” is a flat computer housing shape with a square form. The term was coined in the 1990s for the SPARC workstations from Sun Microsystems with their elegant shapes that actually look like a pizza box.</item>
        <item>Douglas Engelbart is said to have invented the computer mouse. Although this is true, he was not the first. Almost exactly at the same time as Engelbart\'s first demo, the Telefunken company commercially launched a mouse with a roller ball. However, at a price of DM 1500, this was reserved for a few specialised users, such as universities.</item>
        <item>Probably the best-known chip of all times is the 7400 by Texas Instruments, which only contained four NAND gates. The 74xx series provides basic logic functions. It is not only extremely popular with hobbyists, but is also widely used in the commercial sector. The newer 74xx and 74xxx chips now contain highly complex circuits, but the oldest types still exist virtually unchanged.</item>
        <item>The first hackers in history were Louis Blanc and his twin brother François, who also developed modern roulette. The Blanc brothers used the Chappe telegraph to transmit information from the Paris stock exchange, which they used for insider trading and made considerable profits. They skilfully used a special character of the Chappe alphabet with the meaning “delete previous character” to hide their information in regular messages. They were convicted in 1836, but not sentenced as there was no law that they had broken.</item>
        <item>It is unworthy of excellent men to lose hours like slaves in the labour of calculation which could safely be relegated to anyone else if machines were used.\n\nGottfried Wilhelm Leibniz, 1685</item>
        <item>An “ultimate machine” has the only purpose to switch off itself. It is often realized as a box with a switch or a lever on it to activate the machine. This will make an arm come out of the box to switch the lever off again.\n\nA famous creator of Ultimate Machines was Claude Shannon together with his student Marvin Minsky. Other “useless machines” were designed already in the 1930s by Bruno Munari.</item>
        <item>Hewlett-Packard was one of the first companies to bring programmable pocket calculators onto the market. They used “Reverse Polish Notation”, which took some time getting used to at first, but allows quick and compact calculation instructions.\n\nHP calculators were also known for their solid and high-quality workmanship. Some of them are still in use today, and even some calculations for ChipDefense were carried out on an HP 11C (built in 1985).</item>
        <item>The earliest programmable pocket calculators were intended for use for serious engineering calculations, but also some games were published for them. For example, there was “Lunar Lander”.\n\nThe calculator would display the height and vertical speed of a lunar module, and the player had to enter the amount of fuel to be burned in the rockets. If you used too few, the lander would eventually crash into the surface; if you used too much, it would run out of fuel and also crash. In this case, the display showed the number 3507. Turned upside down, this reads LOSE.</item>
        <item>The Incas in South America used their very own way of storing and processing data. Their quipus consisted of a complex system of many threads and various knots that could be used to record numbers and even perform arithmetic operations.\n\nQuipus were mainly used for bookkeeping, but they also served as calendars.</item>
        <item>Computers do not necessarily have to be electronic devices. Any system that can map basic logical functions such as NOT, OR, AND is at least theoretically capable of performing all the tasks of a computer.\n\nThese can be mechanical structures made of ropes and pulleys, or a card game with appropriate rules, or redstone circuits in Minecraft. Even the cellular patterns in Conway\'s Game Of Life can map a digital computer - but you need a really, really huge playing field for that.</item>
        <item>The term “electronic” comes from the ancient Greek word ἤλεκτρον (“electron”), which means “amber”. This is actually a fossilised resin that is used as jewellery.\n\nIn contrast, “algorithm” is a word that looks very Greek, but is not. Around 800, the important mathematician Al-Khwarizmi lived in Baghdad, whose works were also translated into Latin. His name was distorted into “Algoritmi”, and this term has stuck.</item>
        <item>The word ‘cyber’ originally comes from seafaring. The ‘cybernator’ (or ‘gubernator’, from the Greek word κυβερνήτης) is the helmsman of a ship. In French, the helm is therefore called ‘gouvernail’. The word ‘governor’ also comes from ‘gubernator’, and therefore shares its origin with ‘cyber’.</item>
        <item>In the INTERCAL programming language, there is - among other absurd instructions - the PLEASE command. It does nothing, but if you don\'t use it often enough, the compiler is annoyed and terminates with an error message.\n\nYou must not write PLEASE too often, however, because then the compiler thinks that you are making fun of it and responds with E099 PROGRAMMER IS OVERLY POLITE.</item>
        <item>In this game, how are the “unwanted chips” placed? Their number is not exactly predetermined, but it is not completely random either.\n\nIt works roughly like this: A target difficulty level is determined for each level. The chips have a value depending on how annoying they are — for example, NOP has 0.5 and DUP 2.0. In addition, the length of the path that the attackers have to travel to the CPU is included in the difficulty (short paths with few slots are considered more difficult).\n\nFor each level, as many chips are placed at random until the specified difficulty is reached. The target difficulty naturally increases as the level increases. On the other hand, each level of Jack Kilby lowers it by 1, meaning that Kilby removes an average of two NOPs or one ADD or half a DUP.</item>
        <item>How many programmers does it take to change a light bulb?\n\nNone. It\'s a hardware problem.</item>
        <item>Our word “robot” goes back to the Czech “robota”, which means “labour”. It was first used in 1920 in the theatre play “R.U.R.” by Karel Čapek.\n\nThe actual inventor of the word is Karel\'s brother Josef Čapek, an important writer, painter, graphic artist and photographer. The Čapek brothers had a significant influence on cultural and political life in Czechoslovakia between the world wars.\n\nJosef Čapek was arrested in 1939 for criticising National Socialism and murdered in the Bergen-Belsen concentration camp in 1945.</item>
        <item>In the game settings you can change the stage numbers to hexadecimal.</item>
        <item>In Anglo-American server rooms, there used to be warning notices that were written in a kind of pseudo-German and were intended as humorous parodies. There were very similar signs in German-speaking countries, but here, consequently, in pseudo-English.\nOne of the many versions read:\n\nACHTUNG!\n\nALLES TURISTEN UND NONTEKNISCHEN LOOKENSPEEPERS!\nDAS KOMPUTERMASCHINE IST NICHT FÜR DER GEFINGERPOKEN UND MITTENGRABEN! ODERWISE IST EASY TO SCHNAPPEN DER SPRINGENWERK, BLOWENFUSEN UND POPPENCORKEN MIT SPITZENSPARKEN. IST NICHT FÜR GEWERKEN BEI DUMMKOPFEN. DER RUBBERNECKEN SIGHTSEEREN KEEPEN DAS COTTONPICKEN HÄNDER IN DAS POCKETS MUSS. ZO RELAXEN UND WATSCHEN DER BLINKENLIGHTS.</item>
        <item>The first programmable desktop calculator came from Ivrea in Italy. At a time when computers were filling entire gymnasiums, the Olivetti company launched the “Programma 101”, which was a fully-fledged computer in the modern sense - even if it looked more like a commercial calculator.\n\nEven earlier was the “Mathatron” from Mathatronics. The exterior of this machine makes a somewhat tinkered impression, and it is not clear whether it was ever sold in large numbers. It also lacked an important feature that the “Programma 101” had: a magnetic card reader that allowed programmes to be saved and loaded.\n\nBoth machines were also revolutionary in that they could be operated using normal mathematical expressions and did not require expert knowledge of machine language.</item>
        <item>The first American computer, ENIAC, was programmed by a team of six high-calibre specialists - all of whom were women. For a long time, their achievements went virtually unrecognised. Only recently has there been an interest in the influence that these women had on the development of computer science.\n\nTheir names are Frances Spence, Betty Holberton, Ruth Teitelbaum, Kathleen Antonelli, Marlyn Meltzer and Jean Bartik.</item>
        <item>Instead of the hexadecimal system, computers can also work internally with ‘normal’ decimal numbers. A decimal digit from 0 to 9 is then coded in four bits, and the six superfluous combinations (A to F) are not used. This representation is called BCD (binary coded decimal) and has the advantage that a memory dump can be read in the familiar number system.\n\nHowever, the disadvantages clearly outweigh the advantages. Around a third of the memory space is wasted and all logic and arithmetic operations become significantly more complicated and require more circuits. The BCD representation is therefore practically no longer used today.</item>
    </string-array>

    <!-- HEROES :: DESCRIPTIONS -->
    <string name="turing">Alan Turing was a foundational figure in computer science who introduced concepts such as the Turing machine and the Turing test and played a crucial role in breaking the Enigma code during World War II. His work shaped modern computing, though his life was tragically cut short after persecution for his homosexuality.</string>
    <string name="lovelace">Ada Lovelace is widely regarded as the first programmer for her work on Charles Babbage’s analytical engine, where she wrote an algorithm for computing Bernoulli numbers. She also foresaw that computers could manipulate symbols beyond pure calculation, anticipating modern software concepts.</string>
    <string name="hollerith">Herman Hollerith pioneered data processing using punched cards, developing machines that revolutionized large-scale data handling, notably for national censuses. His company later evolved into IBM, one of the most influential technology firms in history.</string>
    <string name="osborne">Adam Osborne created the first commercially successful portable computer, the Osborne 1, in 1981, combining all essential components into a single transportable unit. He was also known as a writer and publisher of computer books.</string>
    <string name="cernettes">Les Horribles Cernettes were a parody pop group at CERN who became the first band featured on the World Wide Web. A photo of the group from 1992 became the first widely distributed web image, helping define early web culture.</string>
    <string name="knuth">Donald Knuth is a computer scientist best known for The Art of Computer Programming, one of the most influential works in the field. In the process, he created the TeX typesetting system, now a standard for scientific and mathematical publishing.</string>
    <string name="zuse">Konrad Zuse built the first programmable, fully automatic digital computer in 1941 and introduced fundamental concepts such as binary logic and floating-point arithmetic. He also designed Plankalkül, the world’s first high-level programming language.</string>
    <string name="franke">Herbert W. Franke was a physicist, science fiction author, and early pioneer of computer art and graphics. He developed the idea of “cybernetic aesthetics,” exploring art generated through algorithms and electronic systems.</string>
    <string name="vaughan">Dorothy Vaughan was a mathematician at NASA who excelled as a “human computer” and later became a supervisor. She prepared her team for the transition to electronic computing by mastering and teaching the FORTRAN programming language.</string>
    <string name="tramiel">Jack Tramiel, a Holocaust survivor, founded Commodore International and helped bring computing to the masses with the Commodore 64. The C64 became the best-selling home computer of all time and introduced millions to personal computing.</string>
    <string name="wiener">Norbert Wiener founded the field of cybernetics, laying the groundwork for artificial intelligence and modern control systems. A prolific mathematician, he later adopted a strong pacifist stance and avoided contributing to military research.</string>
    <string name="pascal">Blaise Pascal was a mathematician, philosopher, and physicist whose mechanical calculators were early steps toward automated computation. His legacy lives on in the Pascal programming language, named in his honor.</string>
    <string name="hopper">Grace Hopper was a computer scientist who pioneered the idea that programs could be written in human-readable languages instead of machine code. She developed the FLOW-MATIC language and created the first compiler, laying the groundwork for modern programming languages.</string>
    <string name="mandelbrot">Benoît Mandelbrot founded fractal geometry, a mathematical approach that describes complex natural forms and enables striking computer-generated graphics. The visualization of the Mandelbrot set became iconic and marked the beginning of a new era of computer art.</string>
    <string name="schneier">Bruce Schneier is a renowned expert in cryptography and information security and the author of influential works such as “Applied Cryptography.” He is also known for openly criticizing governments and corporations when he believes they threaten security or privacy.</string>
    <string name="meier">Sid Meier is a game designer who revolutionized strategy games by simulating complex systems with simple rules. His games, especially the “Civilization” series, tell sweeping stories of human history and have shaped the genre for decades.</string>
    <string name="kilby">Jack St. Clair Kilby invented the integrated circuit, combining multiple electronic components into a single chip and enabling modern microelectronics. He is also regarded as a co-inventor of the pocket calculator and the thermal printer.</string>
    <string name="chappe">Claude Chappe and his brothers developed the optical telegraph, the first system capable of transmitting information rapidly over long distances. By the early 19th century, their semaphore network connected Paris with major cities across France and Europe.</string>
    <string name="hamilton">Margaret Hamilton led the software development for NASA’s Apollo missions, where her team programmed the guidance computers for the spacecraft and lunar module. She coined the term “software engineering” and helped establish software reliability as a critical discipline.</string>
    <string name="leibniz">Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz was a polymath who made lasting contributions to science, mathematics, and philosophy. For computing, he built advanced mechanical calculators and recognized the importance of binary numbers, which form the basis of all digital systems.</string>
    <string name="ohm">Georg Simon Ohm mathematically described the relationship between voltage, current, and resistance, a principle now known as Ohm’s law. Although initially ignored, his work became fundamental to electrical engineering, and the unit of resistance is named after him.</string>
    <string name="volta">Alessandro Volta was a physicist who made foundational discoveries in electricity and developed the first functional battery. His work defined key electrical concepts, and the unit of electrical voltage, the volt, bears his name.</string>
    <string name="shannon">Claude Shannon founded information theory and helped make digital computing possible by applying Boolean logic to electrical circuits. He defined information and entropy, contributed to cryptography and artificial intelligence, and even built machines that could solve puzzles and learn.</string>
    <string name="boole">George Boole formalized logical reasoning into a mathematical system now known as Boolean algebra, which underpins all modern computer logic. Despite little formal education, he taught himself multiple languages and advanced mathematics.</string>
    <string name="diffie">Whitfield Diffie, together with Martin Hellman, invented public-key cryptography and the Diffie–Hellman key exchange, enabling secure communication over the Internet. He is also a strong advocate for privacy and civil liberties.</string>
    <string name="conway">John Horton Conway was a mathematician best known for creating Conway’s Game of Life, a simple system that produces complex, lifelike patterns. Beyond recreational mathematics, he also made significant contributions to several serious mathematical fields.</string>
    <string name="neumann">John von Neumann was one of the fathers of computer science and the main contributor to the von Neumann architecture, which defines how modern computers combine memory, processing, and program control. A brilliant mathematician, he also shaped quantum mechanics and game theory, though his legacy is complicated by his involvement in military research and weapons development.</string>

    <!-- HEROES :: WIKIPEDIA -->
    <string name="url_wikipedia_fallback">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Main_Page</string>
    <string name="url_turing">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alan_Turing</string>
    <string name="url_lovelace">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Ada_Lovelace</string>
    <string name="url_hollerith">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Herman_Hollerith</string>
    <string name="url_franke">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Herbert_W._Franke</string>
    <string name="url_osborne">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Adam_Osborne</string>
    <string name="url_tramiel">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Tramiel</string>
    <string name="url_mandelbrot">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Benoit_Mandelbrot</string>
    <string name="url_hamilton">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Margaret_Hamilton_(software_engineer)</string>
    <string name="url_pascal">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Blaise_Pascal</string>
    <string name="url_conway">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_Horton_Conway</string>
    <string name="url_lhc">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Les_Horribles_Cernettes</string>
    <string name="url_vaughan">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Dorothy_Vaughan</string>
    <string name="url_schneier">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Bruce_Schneier</string>
    <string name="url_diffie">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Whitfield_Diffie</string>
    <string name="url_zuse">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Konrad_Zuse</string>
    <string name="url_meier">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Sid_Meier</string>
    <string name="url_kilby">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Jack_Kilby</string>
    <string name="url_neumann">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/John_von_Neumann</string>
    <string name="url_knuth">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Donald_Knuth</string>
    <string name="url_hopper">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Grace_Hopper</string>
    <string name="url_leibniz">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Gottfried_Wilhelm_Leibniz</string>
    <string name="url_chappe">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Claude_Chappe</string>
    <string name="url_ohm">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Georg_Ohm</string>
    <string name="url_volta">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Alessandro_Volta</string>
    <string name="url_shannon">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Claude_Shannon</string>
    <string name="url_wiener">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Norbert_Wiener</string>
    <string name="url_boole">https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/George_Boole</string>

    <!-- _________________________________________________________________________________ -->


    <string name="shortdesc_SUB">SUB :: Chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_startinfo">Starting information</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_info_on_kill">Additional info</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_SHR">SHR :: Chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_ACC">ACC :: Chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_MEM">MEM :: Chip speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_RES">Resistance value</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_duration">Resistance effect duration</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_heat">Generated heat</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_upgrade">Chip upgrade cost</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_lives">Additional lives</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_frequency">Attacker frequency</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_att_speed">Attacker speed</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_att_strength">Attacker strength</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_coin_strength">Coin strength</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_info_gain">Information gain</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_heat_conversion">heat converted</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_double_chance">%s double hit chance</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_range">%s chip range</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_refund">Refund when selling chips</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_max_hero_upgrade">Max hero level</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_limit_unwanted">Unwanted chip count</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_create_wanted">Additional chip count</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_reduce_removal">Chip removal cost</string>
    <string name="shortdesc_enable_mem_upgrade">MEM max. level</string>
    <string name="upgrade_format">%1$s [cost: %2$d]</string>
    <string name="stage_number">Stage %s</string>
    <string name="toast_stage_cleared">Stage cleared</string>
    <string name="toast_enter_stage">Stage %s</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_CHIPSPEED">Decreases cooldown time of all %s chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_HEAT">Reduces the amount of generated heat</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_STARTINFO">Increases information at start of level</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_UPGRADECOST">Reduces upgrade cost of all chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_LIVES">Grants additional lives</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_FREQUENCY">Decreases attacker frequency</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_INFOOVERTIME">Gains additional bits over time</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_ATTSPEED">Reduces attacker speed</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_COINSTRENGTH">Reduces cryptocoin strength</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_ATTSTRENGTH">Reduces attacker strength</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_MAXHEROUPGRADE">Increases maximal upgrade level of other heroes</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_REFUNDPRICE">Increases refund when selling chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_GAININFO">Increases information gain through destroying attackers</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_RANGE">Increases %s chip range</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_LIMITUNWANTED">Reduces the number of unwanted chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_CREATE_CHIPS">Creates additional chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_DECREASEREMOVAL">Reduces the cost of unwanted chip removal</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_ENABLEMEM">Enables upgrading of MEM chips</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_RES_STRENGTH">Increases the strength of resistors</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_RES_DURATION">Increases the duration of resistance effect</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_CONVERT_HEAT">Converts some of the resistors\' heat into info</string>
    <string name="HERO_EFFECT_CHANCE_DOUBLE">Gives %s chips a chance of double effect</string>

    <string name="coins_singular">one coin</string>
    <string name="coins_plural">%d coins</string>
    <string name="coins_none">no coins</string>
    <string name="deco">Deco</string>
</resources>